Why?
Why did this happen?
Nezuko, don't die on me.
Don't die.
I'll definitely save you!
I won't let you die.
Tanjiro.
Your face is dirty.
Come over here.
It gets dangerous because of the snow.
It's okay if you don't go.
I want everyone to be full
during New Year.
I want to sell more charcoal.
Thank you.
Tanjiro!
Are you going to the town today?
I want to tag along too!
You can't.
You both can't walk
as fast as Tanjiro, right?
Mom!
No way.
We can't pull the carriage out today.
You can't sit and rest on it.
Tanjiro!
I want to go with you.
I'll help you sell the charcoal too.
Thank you, Hanako.
But you should stay home today.
Shigeru too.
I'll buy delicious food for you.
Really?
Yes.
Hanako, I'll read a book to you
when I return home.
Okay.
Good girl.
Thank you, Tanjiro.
I'll get going then.
Takeo.
If you don't mind,
can you chop some firewood for me?
I can chop the firewood.
I just want to do it with you.
Good boy.
What are you doing?
Takeo is embarrassed!
Shut up!
Good boy.
Don't touch my head!
Come back quickly!
Be careful on the road!
Tanjiro.
Nezuko.
I put Rokuta to sleep.
Or else, he'll cry and make noise.
I think he's feeling lonely
after Dad's passing.
That's why everyone clings to you.
Come back safely!
Living isn't easy.
But we're happy.
But life is like the weather.
It's ever-changing.
Sunny days won't last forever.
It won't keep on snowing too.
But when happiness comes crashing down,
it's always
accompanied by the smell of blood.
It's Tanjiro.
You still came down the mountain
in this weather?
You're so hardworking.
Don't catch a cold.
I'm fine with this weather.
Want to buy some charcoal?
Do you have enough at home?
Hey, Tanjiro!
I want to buy charcoal.
You helped me fix my door last time.
Thank you.
I also want to buy charcoal.
Tanjiro! You came at the right time.
I was treated as the culprit
who broke the plate.
Please help me!
Smell it.
I smelled a cat.
I told you!
My goodness, it was the cat's fault.
I told you that it wasn't me!
Tanjiro.
Could you help me move some stuff?
It's already late.
But thank goodness,
I sold all the charcoal.
Tanjiro!
Are you going back to the mountain?
It's too dangerous. Don't go.
I have a good nose. I'll be fine.
You can stay the night here.
Come.
Come here.
But...
Just come.
The demons are coming out.
Thank you for the meal.
Well, Mr. Saburo.
What do you mean by demons?
Since a long time ago, man-eating demons
always come out after sunset.
So, you mustn't wander outside at night.
Sleep after you're done.
Wake up early tomorrow and go home.
The demons can't enter houses, right?
No, they can.
If so, everyone will be eaten
by the demons.
That's why there are demon slayers
who help us to kill them.
They have existed a long time ago.
I'll put the light out.
Go to sleep.
Mr. Saburo's whole family passed away.
He has been living alone.
He must be lonely.
I'll bring my brothers here next time.
There's nothing to be afraid of.
There are no demons in this world.
Everything will be fine.
But come to think of it,
Grandma said similar things
before she passed away.
Be careful on the road.
When happiness comes crashing down,
it's always...
The smell of blood.
Nezuko!
What's wrong?
What happened?
What happened here?
Mom.
Hanako.
Takeo.
Shigeru.
Nezuko.
Rokuta.
Only Nezuko's body feels warm.
If I take her to the doctor,
maybe she can be saved.
Why did this happen?
Was it a bear?
Did the non-hibernating bear come out?
I can't breathe.
Breathing in the cold air
is hurting my lungs.
I must move forward.
I need to walk faster.
It's still a long way from the town.
I need to hurry.
I can't let Nezuko die.
I'll definitely save you.
I will save you!
Damn it!
The snow saved me.
But I slipped because of the snow too.
Nezuko.
Nezuko, are you okay?
You don't have to walk.
I'll piggyback you to the town.
Nezuko!
This is...
a demon.
Now I remember what Mr. Saburo said.
Nezuko is a man-eating demon.
It can't be.
Nezuko is a human.
She's a human since she was born.
But she doesn't smell
like the usual Nezuko.
No, Nezuko didn't do that
because she protected Rokuta
and fell on the ground.
Her mouth and hands
weren't stained with blood.
Plus, there's another...
Another smell.
Nezuko's body is growing bigger!
She's getting stronger too.
When I was sleeping comfortably
in someone else's house,
everyone was experiencing
a terrible incident.
It must have hurt.
It must have been horrible.
I'm sorry for not saving everyone.
But at the very least,
I can do something for Nezuko.
But she's so strong.
I can't fight back.
Nezuko!
You can do it, Nezuko!
Endure it! Do it for me!
Don't become a demon!
Hang in there!
You can do it!
What happened?
Who are you?
A katana?
DESTROY DEMONS
Why did you protect her?
My younger sister.
She's my younger sister!
Nezuko!
Is that your sister?
Don't move.
My job is slaying vile demons.
Of course, I also need
to chop off your sister's head.
Hang on.
Nezuko didn't kill anyone.
My house has another smell
that I have never smelled before.
It killed everyone.
I think that must be the case!
It wasn't Nezuko!
Although I don't know
why she become like this,
but...
The reason is simple.
When the demon's blood touches
her wound, she'll become a demon.
That's how man-eating demons
grow their numbers.
Nezuko won't eat people!
I can't believe you said that.
Weren't you almost eaten by her?
No!
Nezuko definitely recognized me.
I won't let anyone hurt her.
Nezuko will become a human again.
I'll definitely cure her!
She's hopeless.
After she becomes a demon,
she can't become a human again.
I'll find it!
I'll definitely find a way.
Don't kill her!
I'll find the one who killed my family.
I'll do all the above!
So...
Don't kill her!
Don't take my family away from me again.
Please stop it.
Please don't kill Nezuko.
I'm begging you.
Please.
Don't let another person take control
of your right to live or die!
Don't beg others pitifully!
If doing so works,
your family wouldn't have been murdered.
When that right is being taken away,
the weak who can't take control
want to cure his younger sister
and find the culprit?
What a joke!
The weak don't have rights or choices.
Even if you go all out,
you'll fall into the hands of the strong.
Maybe the demons will know
the method to cure your sister.
But don't dream that the demons
will respect your will and request.
Of course, I also won't respect you.
This is the reality.
Why did you let her push you
to the ground just now?
Were you protecting your sister?
Why didn't you swing your ax?
Why did you turn your back against me?
Your sister was taken
because of your failure.
I should have pierced you and your sister.
Don't cry.
Don't lose hope.
You shouldn't be doing those things now.
I know you can't take the blow again.
Your family was murdered.
Your sister become a man-eating demon.
Are you hurt?
Do you want to scream your heart out?
I understand.
If I arrived here half a day earlier,
maybe your family wouldn't have to die.
But I can't turn back the time.
Unleash your fury.
The powerful and pure rage
of unforgiveness
will become an unwavering force
driving your limbs.
A fragile will
won't be able to protect
and cure your sister
or avenge your family.
Stop...
Stop it!
A simple attack driven by emotions.
How dumb.
Where's his ax?
Before running into the woods,
not only did he threw a rock,
but he also threw his ax.
To avoid being discovered he was unarmed,
he slanted his body
so that I couldn't see his hand.
He knew he couldn't beat me.
He wanted to knock me down
when I slashed at him.
This guy...
Damn it!
He'll be eaten!
Nezuko.
Nezuko is different.
She won't eat people!
Someone said the same thing back then.
He was eaten in the end.
In the state of hunger,
demons will eat their family members
because they have high nutrition values.
Who knows how many times
have I seen this scene?
This girl is wounded.
She's using energy to heal herself.
When she became a demon,
she must have consumed a lot of energy.
Without a doubt,
she's in a state of severe hunger.
She can't wait
to eat human flesh right now.
Her protective action.
Her intimidation towards me.
Maybe this pair of siblings
are different after all.
I'm sorry for leaving you behind.
Tanjiro.
I'm leaving Nezuko in your hands.
Are you awake?
Go to the foot of Sagiri Mountain.
Find an old man called Sakonji Urokodaki.
Tell him that Giyu Tomioka sent you.
There's no sunlight now so she's fine.
But don't bring her out in the sun.
Let's go.
Subtitle translation by Michelle Chai